

# **Dedan Msafari**

JavaScript, React and React Native Engineer, UI/UX Designer.

Komarock, Nairobi, 2823-00200, Kenya 0723275041 · <u>dedan.msafari@gmail.com</u>

Github, LinkedIn

Date / Place of birth 31/01/1998, Westlands, Nairobi

#### **Nationality**

Kenyan

#### Skills

Management Skills

**Public Speaker** 

**Quality Assuarance** 

Quick Learner

Front-End Development

UI/UX designer

React-Native Engineer

#### Hobbies

Playing Chess, Watching Ancient History movies Listening to philosophers of the middle ages listening to podcasts. Writing Stories.

#### Languages

English

Kiswahili

### **Profile**

I am a **Front-end Engineer, React Native Engineer and UI/UX Designer** .I have profession experience building design mock-ups and prototypes using Figma. I have experience working with major front-end tools including the Jam-stack, graphQL and styling libraries i.e Material-UI and Styled components. I have a great foundation and core understanding of JavaScript. I have great working knowledge of React-Native, MongoDB and Firebase.

# **Employment History**

#### UI/UX Developer, TouchInspiration, Nairobi

September 2021 - April 2022

I Designed based on client requirements, simple and intuitive user interfaces that enable users to achieve their desired goals. I was especially fond of seamless mobile designs.

Among my most memorable moments was where:-

- I Settled any client disputes in a professional and pleasant manner.
- I Worked to ensure a positive and stress-free user experience.

#### **Consultant Software Engineer, Nairobi**

April 2022 — July 2022

- Researched extensively on current technological trends in order to advice designers and engineers on best practices and technologies to use.
- I assisted developers in coming up with great designs for their mobile applications. This was done by correcting and redesigning previously sub optimal designs.
- Through constant communication i was able to improve my social skills,my understanding and attention to details, empathy levels and overall interpersonal skills.

#### Mobile Applications Engineer, Nairobi

August 2022 - February 2023

- Using my previous experience as a UI/UX Designer.I came up with simple and intuitive wire-frames, mock-ups and user stories for a social networking mobile app called Localize.

- Using React-Native I built the core of the First iteration of the mobile application using tools such as react-navigation and styled-components.
- -I learnt and implemented proper folder structuring and how to build reusable components to be used in multiple files. This resulted in easily readable and organized code.

### **Education**

#### **Bsc Computer Science, Egerton University, Nakuru**

August 2016 — December 2020

Graduated with High Honors in my bachelors in Computer Science. I learnt alot about the IT industry and its eco-systems and with this knowledge i am ready to change the community using my technology skills.

#### Complete UI/UX Designer, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

January 2021 - March 2021

Learnt How to design User Interfaces with Figma. I was able to quickly move from Idea to design. I understood how to put users first while designing so as to bring about a seamless experience in client applications.

#### Javascript Mastery, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

April 2021 — June 2021

Learnt advanced patterns in Javascript, how to understand complex syntax and using functional programming to come up with great applications.

# **Attachment and Internships**

#### Junior Software Engineer, Ongair, Nairobi

June 2019 - August 2019

under supervision from senior developers, I was able to implement features my most notable being adding a fully fledged button from its front-end to its back-end implementation on an existing Saas system. This was my first time gaining industry level experience and i learnt a lot. I worked with React Js and it was one of the best UI libraries i had ever seen.

## References

ROSE MACHARIA from EACC(Ethics and Anti Corruption Comission) 0721345556

ELIZABETH KHAHOYA from HELB(Higher Education Loans Board) 0722959179

ROSE MWAVISWA from Miller and Miller Company 0721276431

### **Others**

My Belief

January 2020 — Present

- I believe in Quality software that anyone can read.
- I believe that hiring empathetic software engineers is Key to the future of any tech company.
- I believe that working towards a certain goal with fellow team members who inspire you is Key to success.

# **Extra-curricular activities**

#### **Sports**

June 2015 — Present

Running, Going for Nature walks,

Playing Football, Cycling and Archery.